Jonathan Kizer

Driven and curious Data Science & Analytics professional with 3+ years of experience creating thoughtful solutions to nuanced and complex problems. Experienced in predictive modeling, data processing, and data visualization, as well as owning multiple projects from discovery to implementation.

Experience

VillageMD - Remote

SENIOR ANALYST, ANALYTICS

DEC 2019 - PRESENT

Working across business functions, I helped position VillageMD's analytics & data science functions for growth into the largest primary care provider in the nation.

- Engineered data & reporting systems to drive 40% yearly improvement in Healthcare Quality
- Assisted in creation of Data Science team, including data environment setup and initial LSTM forecasting, causal inference workstreams
- Standardized patient assignment to physicians, improving patient experience and continuity of care
- Implemented and managed Physician Incentive program, aligning doctor compensation with company goals and improved patient healthcare
- Served as internal consultant, SME to broader company to ensure data integrity was preserved throughout "growth phase

VillageMD - Houston, TX

HEALTH INFORMATICS ANALYST

MAY 2019 - DEC 2019

- Created Physician reporting package, and automated delivery to 200+ physicians on a monthly basis
- Developed process to validate inbound data sources for normalization within data warehouse environment
- Informed new clinic locations via patient geographic location clustering
- Engineered process to load data into Salesforce to manage medication adherence in population

VillageMD - Houston, TX

STRATEGY & OPERATIONS ANALYST

2018 - 2019

- Managed patient outreach efforts to generate patient engagement
- Developed scheduling tool to optimize at-home healthcare provider routes
- Validated data sets for normalization, visualization and use in clinical settings

Personal Projects

2019

PDR - PHOTO DATA REMOVER

Developed and shipped iOS app to remove image EXIF data (location, date, etc.) to improve online privacy

2018-2019

PHOTOLOCATE

Developed and shipped iOS app that allows users to set a location for imported photos

CONTACT

jk@jonathankizer.com jonathankizer.com (512) 902-1843 Boulder, CO

EDUCATION

2020-2023

Georgia Institute of TechnologyMaster of Science, Analytics

2018

The University of Texas at Austin BBA, Supply Chain Management Elements of Computer Science Core Texts and Ideas

SKILLS

DATA ANALYSIS

SQL & Data Warehousing T-SQL, POSTGRESQL, Snowflake

Visualization

Tableau, D3.js, ggplot2, MatPlotLib

Predictive Time-Series Modeling ARIMA, ARCH/GARCH, LSTM, etc.

Statistical Modeling

Distribution Fitting

Machine Learning Modeling Simulation Techniques

PROGRAMMING

Python

Pandas, Numpy, Tensorflow, SciPy

R

ggplot2, Dplyr, Tidyr, Shiny

Swift

Julia

Java

Git/GitHub